HASSAN SAJJAD

sajjadhassa389@gmail.com | +92-313-1512-576 | +92-334-0107-699

Address: House#618, St#39/Mohan-Pura/Rawalpindi

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Highly motivated BSSE graduate with a strong foundation in Programming and Programming Principles and want to be part of competitive professional environment where I can exploit my inborn ability of accepting challenges. I am keen to enhance my skills through real practical experience. I want to work for an organization that could utilize my existing professional study, experience, and provide a learning environment for building new skills.

Education	Year	Institute/University
BSSE	2018-2022	Foundation University Islamabad (CGPA -3.2)
Intermediate	2015-17	Sir Syed College Rawalpindi (75%)
Matriculation	2013-2015	Sir Syed School Rawalpindi (82%)

PROJECTS

Semester Projects

- Calculator in C++ (Programming Fundamentals)
- Police Department Project (Database)
- Hospital Management System (ISE)
- Trading Bot (Data-Science)
- Portfolio Website (Web-Engineering)
- CMS Application (Mobile App Development)

Final year project

Web-Application

Purpose: A Web Application name Electronic Document Management Portal (EDMP)is An Internet-based document management system. This document management system allows document to be stored on an Internet-accessible server and accessed using web browser, downloaded for review or manipulation, and then can be shared for access by further users.

EDMP provides an efficient way to automatically import, categorize, store, search, retrieve and archive electronic documents. EDMP also allows the users to view and save different versions of the same document and provides a means for freeing up storage space and reducing the costs of paper document copying and distribution.

Technology used: J-Query, AJAX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript for front end and My-Sql for back end

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

- C#
- Java
- C++
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- J-query
- PHP
- Node Js
- React
- Express
- Next
- Docker

Data Bases:

- SQL/NO-SQL
- Oracle
- Mongo-DB
- Postgres

Software's/Tools IDEs:

- Visual Studio
- NetBeans
- Visual Studio Code

Languages:

- ☐ English (Native/ (ILR Level 5)
- ☐ Urdu (Conversational)

Professional Experience

Programming Studio

Development Intern- React JS Team

Rawalpindi, Punjab Aug 2021 – Oct 2021

- Developing and redesigning applications frontend in Bootstrap with material design
- Develop responsive UIs for Desktop, Tablet, and Phone.
- Ensuring high performance UI on mobile and desktop.
- Coordinating with the back-end developers in the process of building the RESTful API.
- Writing code to communicate with external Web Services (Web API).
- Coding tested, idiomatic, and documented JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Writing and debugging code that will work across different browser.

BLS Solutions

Junior Developer - Client Application Team

Rawalpindi, Punjab Aug 2022 – Dec 2022

- Built UI components in React.js
- Learn how to deal with States, Hooks, Props
- Fix Ui Bugs in Company's Project ReactJS
- Implement Redux in Company's Project.
- Worked with Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery Pipelines
- Deploy AWS Elastic Load Balancing in Company's Project
- Works with Redux (Thunk) and Next JS as well
- Used Swagger, Postman in Company's Project for API testing.

CyberSoft Vantage

MERN Stack Developer - Client Application Team

Islamabad, Pakistan Jan 2023 – Present

- Built UI components in React.js
- Learn how to deal with States, Hooks, Props
- Fix Ui Bugs in Company's Project ReactJS
- Implement Redux in Company's Project.
- Worked with Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery Pipelines
- Deploy AWS Elastic Load Balancing in Company's Project
- Works with Redux (Thunk) and Next JS as well
- Used Swagger, Postman in Company's Project for API testing.